<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Ember.js | Jesse Cravens]]></title>
  <link href="http://jessecravens.com/blog/categories/ember-dot-js/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jessecravens.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-16T09:43:15-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://jessecravens.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jesse Cravens]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[jesse.cravens@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[HTML5 and Ember.js at Øredev 2013:The Arts in Malmö, Sweden]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessecravens.com/blog/2013/12/07/html5-and-ember-dot-js-at-oredev-2013-the-arts-malmo/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-07T23:25:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessecravens.com/blog/2013/12/07/html5-and-ember-dot-js-at-oredev-2013-the-arts-malmo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At the beginning of November, I was given an opportunity to give two talks in Malmö, Sweden at the Øredev conference. First of all, I have to say I was extremely impressed with the conference. Although the theme was the Arts, I found it to be a developer&rsquo;s conference with an artsy edge. The speakers I had a chance to see were developer&rsquo;s developers, one of my favorites being a talk on Meteor by Chris Mather (@eventedmind) of <a href="http://eventedmind.com">eventedmind.com</a>. I&rsquo;ve maintained a peripheral view of Meteor, so it was good to get a beginner to intermediate overview of its capabilities. Given that I have been doing <a href="http://www.mongodb.com/">MongoDB</a> / <a href="https://github.com/emberjs/data">Ember-data</a> client work as of lately, I am particularly interested in exploring <a href="https://github.com/slacy/minimongo">minimongo</a>.</p>

<p><img class="imgR400" alt="Øredev 2013 HTML5 Hacks" src="http://jessecravens.com/images/oredev/html5hacks-oredev.jpg"></p>

<p>The city of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Malm%C3%B6">Malmö</a> was also a pleasure to experience, and as you might imagine, the people of Sweden were very welcoming. One of the highlights for me was the speaker dinner at the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Jorchr-Malm%C3%B6_r%C3%A5dhus.jpg">Malmö City Hall</a>, originally constructed in the Middle Ages. On a side note, I finally had a chance to meet and have dinner with <a href="http://www.crockford.com/">Douglass Crockford</a>, a long time inspiration and virtual mentor, who was in town to give the keynote on <a href="http://oredev.org/2013/wed-fri-conference/managing-asynchronicity-with-rq">Managing Async with RQ</a>.</p>

<p>My first talk was a preview of my new book <a href="https://github.com/emberjsbook">O'Reilly&rsquo;s Building Web Apps with Ember.js</a>. I shared the stage with co-author and fellow frog, <a href="http://bashmodernquantity.com/about/">Thomas Q. Brady</a>. We took the audience through the creation of <a href="https://github.com/emberjsbook/rocknrollcall">RocknRollCall</a>, an intermediate level <a href="http://emberjs.com/">Ember.js</a> application that fills in many of the blanks that most of the &lsquo;Getting Started&rsquo; applications don&rsquo;t.</p>

<p><img class="imgL400" alt="O'Reilly's Building Web Apps with Ember.js" src="http://jessecravens.com/images/oredev/ember_cover_600.png"></p>

<p>Some of the highlights of the book, and the talk, cover topics such as: a survey of Ember tooling, debugging with the <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/ember-inspector/bmdblncegkenkacieihfhpjfppoconhi?hl=en">Ember Inspector</a>, Ember boilerplates, app initializers, promises in Ember, the needs API, Ember components, 3rd Party JavaScript Integration (<a href="http://jquery.com/">jQuery</a>, <a href="http://d3js.org/">D3</a>), Ember testing, SPA authentication, <a href="https://github.com/emberjs/data">Ember-data</a> and other client-side persistence solutions, and remote data persistence with Ruby On Rails and Node.js.</p>

<p>My second talk was <a href="http://html5hacks.com/">HTML5 Hacks</a> Evolved, where I continue to share more hacks from by first book <a href="http://html5hacks.com">HTML5 Hacks</a>, and <a href="http://html5hacks.com/">html5hacks.com</a>. This talk is culmination of HTML5 specifications that will have you rethinking browser-based applications. Some of the highlights of this talk included: Web Workers, WebSocket w/ GeoLocation, Device Orientation, and LeapJS, Web Components / Polymer / Ember Components (Custom Elements, Shadow DOM, HTML Imports, Model Driven Views, and Local Storage.</p>

<p>In 2014, I&rsquo;m retiring the HTML5 Hacks talks, to begin focusing solely on Single Page Application development in 2014. My hope is to kick out an early release of <a href="https://github.com/emberjsbook">Building Web Apps with Ember.js</a> very soon, and finish the book in early 2014. After that I&rsquo;ll be in Louisville, KY at <a href="http://www.codepalousa.com/">Code PaLOUsa</a> to continue the Ember.js roadtrip.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ember.js Views and Live Templates with Handlebars.js Part 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessecravens.com/blog/2013/06/04/ember-dot-js-views-and-live-templates-with-handlebars-dot-js-part-1/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-04T10:05:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessecravens.com/blog/2013/06/04/ember-dot-js-views-and-live-templates-with-handlebars-dot-js-part-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="imgL200" alt="Tech-pro Ember.js Views" src="http://tpstatic.com/img/usermedia/cHI1WdevsEyBJ7dLfmVUdA/cropped-w220-h220.png"></p>

<p>This is an exploration of Handlebars.js template library when used with Ember.js views. Many of the Handlebars.js tutorials on the web discuss the Handlebars API, but not in the specific context of using Handlebars with Ember.js. In addition to filling that void, I&rsquo;ll also give a brief background of JavaScript templating in general to provide perspective as to the problems it is solving.</p>

<p>This tutorial will be divided into two parts. In Part 1, you should gain a clear understanding of JavaScript templates, the capabilities of Handlebars expressions and helpers, and how to write your own Handlebars helpers.</p>

<p>Read more at: <a href="http://tech.pro/tutorial/1308/emberjs-views-and-live-templates-with-handlebarsjs-part-1">http://tech.pro/tutorial/1308/emberjs-views-and-live-templates-with-handlebarsjs-part-1</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Modern Ember.js Application Workflow with Yeoman and Mocha]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessecravens.com/blog/2013/04/23/modern-ember-dot-js-application-workflow-with-yeoman-and-mocha/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-23T10:05:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessecravens.com/blog/2013/04/23/modern-ember-dot-js-application-workflow-with-yeoman-and-mocha</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="imgL200" alt="Tech-pro Modern Ember.js Application Workflow" src="http://tpstatic.com/img/usermedia/LgFpf2qDCkGfHlDBR4oGDA/cropped-w220-h220.png"></p>

<p>The following tutorial will provide an overview for building Ember.js applications with Yeoman. Keep in mind, Yeoman is a framework agnostic collection of tools, used to manage the workflow of any JavaScript application or plugin. For the sake of this tutorial, we have chosen to focus on Ember.js, as a case study.</p>

<p>Our workflow would not be complete without also setting up our testing strategy, so we will also include a standard BDD (Behavior Driven Development) setup with the Mocha testing framework.</p>

<p>Read more at: <a href="http://tech.pro/tutorial/1249/modern-emberjs-application-workflow-with-yeoman-and-mocha">http://tech.pro/tutorial/1249/modern-emberjs-application-workflow-with-yeoman-and-mocha</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
