<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: BCP | Jesse Cravens]]></title>
  <link href="http://jessecravens.com/blog/categories/bcp/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jessecravens.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-02T17:24:29-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://jessecravens.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jesse Cravens]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[jesse.cravens@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[EduPunk]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessecravens.com/blog/2009/03/15/edupunk/"/>
    <updated>2009-03-15T12:22:26-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessecravens.com/blog/2009/03/15/edupunk</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<object width="445" height="364"><param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/f7MxVqe_uRI&hl=en&fs=1&border=1"></param><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"></param><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"></param><embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/f7MxVqe_uRI&hl=en&fs=1&border=1" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" width="445" height="364"></embed></object>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[In Search of A Balance: Integrating the Sudbury and other democratic models with Moodle]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessecravens.com/blog/2006/11/17/in-search-of-a-balance-integrating-the-sudbury-and-other-democratic-models-with-moodle/"/>
    <updated>2006-11-17T06:57:33-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessecravens.com/blog/2006/11/17/in-search-of-a-balance-integrating-the-sudbury-and-other-democratic-models-with-moodle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm definitely into the hybrid thing lately. Hybrid instruction not only in the sense of implementation: online and face to face learning through moodle (http://moodle.org) and short class lectures/discussions, but also philosophically in a sense of allowing students to have some type of control over the curriculum, and direction of their own study. Every moodle assignment I offer, is open to interpretation and creativity. This is why I believe that rubrics can potentially take the fun out of learning. They limit learners to the parameters made by the teacher. Especially when we are teaching technoloies that are more native to the learner than the educator. <br /><br />This article takes a neutral approach to - what I will call the Sudbury model, but really applies to many other free, democratic school models. I agree with both sides of the argument, and I have settled on balance and moderation of both freedom and standardization. This combined with a balance between face to face and elearning and I think we might make some real progress in my classroom. <br /><a href="http://www.edutopia.org/magazine/ed1article.php?id=Art_1615&amp;issue=oct_06">Free Radicals</a> <br /> <blockquote>In the country's most alternative classrooms, there's no such thing as a report card.</p>

<br /><br />Sudbury schools are only one variety of so-called free, or democratic, schools, which eschew most conventions of traditional education in favor of a much more radical program. At most free schools, literally every decision, from those about staff hiring and firing to determinations concerning rules, facilities, and budget issues, is made by the entire school community in a one-person, one-vote process. There are no tests, no report cards, no requirements, and no classes -- and no curriculum, other than what students set for themselves.




<br /><br />It is a philosophy that may strike the uninitiated as far-fetched, if not irresponsible, but it seems to be working.......

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[iBoerne.com selected for 2007 TCEA Convention student showcase]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessecravens.com/blog/2006/11/15/iboerne-com-selected-for-2007-tcea-convention-student-showcase/"/>
    <updated>2006-11-15T07:36:10-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessecravens.com/blog/2006/11/15/iboerne-com-selected-for-2007-tcea-convention-student-showcase</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Congratulations to my students for their great work on iBoerne.com. Our submission for Student Showcase
has been accepted for the 2007 TCEA Convention !<br /><br /><a href="http://jessecravens.com/node/79">iBoerne.com: an Interactive Online Game for Programming Students | jessecravens.com</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[EdTech Connect Webinar Series| DiscoverySchool.com]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessecravens.com/blog/2006/11/10/edtech-connect-webinar-series-discoveryschool-com/"/>
    <updated>2006-11-10T13:19:36-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessecravens.com/blog/2006/11/10/edtech-connect-webinar-series-discoveryschool-com</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://school.discovery.com/edtechconnect/">EdTech Connect Webinar Series| DiscoverySchool.com</a> <br /> <blockquote>EdTechConnect is a free webinar series to help teachers integrate media and technology into the classroom. Discovery Education connects you with the experts who will answer your questions and bring you new insights. All you need is a telephone and a computer connected to the Internet and a cadre of experts will virtually join you at your desk. EdTechConnect webinars have featured Alan November, Kathy Schrock, Hall Davidson, Steve Dembo and most recently, Joe Brennan.</p>

<p>Mark your calendars now! Coming soon to EdTechConnect, David Warlick on November 15th and Will Richardson on December 13th.</blockquote><br /><br /><p class="poweredbyperformancing">powered by <a href="http://performancing.com/firefox">performancing firefox</a></p></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[20 Ideas for Integrating Technology into the Classroom]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessecravens.com/blog/2006/11/10/20-ideas-for-integrating-technology-into-the-classroom/"/>
    <updated>2006-11-10T10:22:08-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessecravens.com/blog/2006/11/10/20-ideas-for-integrating-technology-into-the-classroom</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://teaching.mrbelshaw.co.uk/index.php/2006/09/11/20-ideas-intro/">20 Ideas: Introduction at teaching.mrbelshaw.co.uk</a><br /><br />Doug Belshaw is creating a great resource for eductors.Take a minute to explore this archive. <br /><br /><br /><p class="poweredbyperformancing">powered by <a href="http://performancing.com/firefox">performancing firefox</a></p></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
