<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Forms | Jesse Cravens]]></title>
  <link href="http://jessecravens.com/blog/categories/forms/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jessecravens.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-25T16:06:59-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://jessecravens.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jesse Cravens]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[jesse.cravens@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fluent Conf 2013: Battle of the HTML5 Hackers]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessecravens.com/blog/2013/06/05/fluent-conf-2013-battle-of-the-html5-hackers/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-05T10:12:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessecravens.com/blog/2013/06/05/fluent-conf-2013-battle-of-the-html5-hackers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Our presentation at Fluent Conference 2013 was a success, as <a href="https://twitter.com/boyofgreen">Jeff</a> and I delivered our final version of the 'Battle of the Hackers' series.</p>

<p><img class="imgR300" alt="Jesse Cravens - Fluent Conf 2013" src="http://jessecravens.com/images/fluent_video.png"></p>

<p>If you missed the conference, you can still catch every workshop, session, and keynote with the complete video compilation of the event.Catch up with this year’s lineup of speakers—seasoned pros as well as notable newcomers—as they share their expertise with JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, and related technologies that power the Web.</p>

<p>You can order the series <a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920030843.do">here</a>.</p>

<p><img class="imgL200" alt="Jesse Cravens - Fluent Conf 2013" src="http://jessecravens.com/images/jesse_fluent.png"></p>

<p>It was a great pleasure to share the stage with Brendan Eich (Mozilla), Paul Irish (Google), Lea Verou (W3C), Bill Scott (PayPal), Jesse Freeman (Microsoft), Dion Almaer (Walmart.com), and dozens more in the field.</p>

<p>We also had a great turn out for the book signing, thanks for all the support. And congrats to Doug Hall for winning a free ebook copy of our book <a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920026273.do">HTML5 Hacks</a></p>

<p><img class="imgR300" alt="Jesse Cravens - Fluent Conf 2013" src="http://jessecravens.com/images/fluent_books.jpg"></p>

<p>As always we've made all the code available and more at <a href="http://html5hacks.com">html5hacks.com</a>, and on github: <a href="http://github.com/html5hacks">github.com/html5hacks</a>.</p>

<p>I also added a few more new hacks, involoving Web Components (Shadow DOM, HTML Imports, Custom Elements) and Polymer.js. You can find that source code available here: <a href="https://github.com/html5hacks/fluent2013-html5hacks">github.com/html5hacks/fluent2013-html5hacks</a></p>

<p>It's been alot of fun co-presenting with Jeff, but my next two sessions, I will be going at HTML5 Hacking solo. You can catch my next presentations in NYC on July 24th–25th at <a href="http://lanyrd.com/2013/devcon5/">Devcon5 2013 NYC</a> or November 4th–8th at <a href="http://lanyrd.com/2013/redev/">Øredev 2013</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SXSWi 2013: 'Battle of the HTML5 Hackers' and 'HTML5 Hacks' Book Signing]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessecravens.com/blog/2013/03/12/sxswi-2013-battle-of-the-html5-hackers/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-12T23:55:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessecravens.com/blog/2013/03/12/sxswi-2013-battle-of-the-html5-hackers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We had a great turnout for the 'Battle of the HTML5 Hackers' presentation at SXSWi on Tuesday.</p>

<p><img class="imgL300" alt="SXSWi 2013: Battle of the HTML5 Hackers - Jesse Cravens and Jeff Burtoft" src="http://jessecravens.com/images/sxsw13/sxsw13-crowd.jpg"></p>

<p>Using our best CDD (Conference Driven Devlopment) techniques, we walked the audience through the creation of <a href="http://nerdclustr.jit.su">Nerdclustr</a>: an HTML5 mobile Application that helps nerds find other like-minded nerds at conferences events.</p>

<p>Using realtime and mapping technolgies, the app visualizes nerd behavior in map pin clusters.</p>

<p><img class="imgR200" alt="Nerdclustr: SXSWi 2013 Ballroom G Austin Convention Center"  src="http://jessecravens.com/images/sxsw13/sxsw13-app.png"></p>

<p>Here is a shot of the app in action (Ballroom G in the Austin Convention Center); it performed well during the presentation. Thanks to <a href="https://www.nodejitsu.com/">Nodjitsu</a> for the quality node.js WebSocket service. After a 2-day hackathon to get the app launched, I ran through a number of deployment options, many of which I have used before for Rails applications. <a href="https://www.nodejitsu.com/">Nodjitsu</a> won out in that it actually supported the WebSokcet protocol and made deployment super simple using the jitsu CLI.</p>

<p><img class="imgL200" alt="Jesse Cravens and Jeff Burtoft: SXSWi 2013 - HTML5 Hacks Book Signing"  src="http://jessecravens.com/images/sxsw13/sxsw13-booksigning.png"></p>

<p>Nerdclustr source code is available <a href="https://github.com/html5hacks/nerd-clustr">here</a>.</p>

<p>During the book signing, the bookstore informed us there were only 3 copies left. I'm not keen to the selection process of books, but I was little surprised at the limited number of technical books. This is certainly a reflection of the SXSWi demographic, and we also tailored our content and presentation style to this audience.</p>

<p>The slide deck is available here:</p>

<script async class="speakerdeck-embed" data-id="c69c92f06d880130bfaa22000a1f8363" data-ratio="1.77777777777778" src="http://jessecravens.com//speakerdeck.com/assets/embed.js"></script>




<hr>


<p>Stay tuned for our next presentation happening online, through O'Reilly Webcasts. Join us for <a href="http://www.oreillynet.com/pub/e/2566">'Rethinking the Possibilities of Browser-based Apps with HTML5'</a> on Wednesday, March 27, 2013 10AM PT.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
