<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Photography | Jesse Cravens]]></title>
  <link href="http://jessecravens.com/blog/categories/photography/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jessecravens.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-26T14:08:09-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://jessecravens.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jesse Cravens]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[jesse.cravens@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[sessionswest.com's 'Morning Surf']]></title>
    <link href="http://jessecravens.com/blog/2006/07/30/sessionswest-coms-morning-surf/"/>
    <updated>2006-07-30T08:01:21-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessecravens.com/blog/2006/07/30/sessionswest-coms-morning-surf</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Another new design for <a href="http://sessionswest.com">SessionsWest.com</a>. I was digging for inspiration for this site, when Jeff called me from San Deigo last week right before he was about to go surfing. </a>The color scheme is known as 'Morning surf,' and I built a custom flash player inspired by the album cover from the Fever Sessions. This new buildout has been my most complex drupal site to date. I embedded a photo gallery, and the mp3 player I mentioned earlier. I used drupal's front page module to give the home page a real clean, simple entry to the site. All in all it doesn't get much more simple, but I think thats what I like about it , and it reflects Jeff's style to the tee.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Texas Hill Country Music as of Lately]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessecravens.com/blog/2006/05/24/texas-hill-country-music-as-of-lately/"/>
    <updated>2006-05-24T17:37:20-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessecravens.com/blog/2006/05/24/texas-hill-country-music-as-of-lately</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.mytexasmusic.com/rodneyjoesmith/"><img src="http://jessecravens.com/images/2006/02/rodneypic250.jpg" style="margin: 10px; float: right; border: 0px" alt="rodneypic250.jpg" align="baseline" width="200" height="247" /></a>This morning I ate breakfast listening to Rodney Joe Smith at our Digett sponsored Boerne Chamber of Commerce Networking Breakfast at <a href="http://enchantedspringsranch.com">Enchanted Springs Ranch</a>.  Boy, Rodney can sing and play. It was a real pleasure.</p>

<p>I also had a pleasure to meet Lynn Myers: Guitar, Fiddle, Vocalist &amp; Band Director of the <a href="http://www.1000hillscc.com/band.html">Thousand Hills Cowboy Church Band</a>.
I love that ol' Country Gospel music and I am looking forward to checking him and the band out soon.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.1000hillscc.com/band.html"><img src="http://jessecravens.com/images/2006/02/2_bandb.jpg" alt="2_bandb.jpg" align="baseline" width="200" height="298" style="margin: 10px; float: left; border: 0px"/></a>This evening, I had a chance to sit down with <a href="http://harleydean.com/index.php">Harley Dean</a> and play some country bass lines from his album, There and Back Again. I like Harley's songwriting and he has a great singing voice.<a href="http://harleydean.com"><img src="http://jessecravens.com/images/2006/02/home_image.jpg" alt="home_image.jpg" style="margin: 10px; float: right; border: 0px" align="baseline" width="220" height="120" /></a></p>

<p>In the meantime, the Digett team will be enjoying the tunes of client, Joel Rafeal (<a href="http://www.joelrafael.com/">http://www.joelrafael.com/</a>) this Friday at the <a href="http://www.kerrvillefolkfestival.com/">Kerrville Folk Festival</a>.</p>

<p>Next week, I'll be at the <a href="http://www.kerrville-music.com/rootsbluesclinic.htm">Roots/Blues Workshop</a> in Kerrville Tues - Thur. I'm looking forward to meeting <a href="http://www.suefoley.com/">Sue Foley,</a> <a href="http://www.thadbeckman.com/">Thad Beckman</a>, <a href="http://www.stevejames.com/">Steve James</a> and the other instructors, and learning some new licks and techniques.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.northernlightsband.com/">The Northern Lights</a> will also be down from New England for the festival. <a href="http://www.northernlightsband.com/"><img src="http://jessecravens.com/images/2006/02/NLband.jpg" alt="NLband.jpg" align="baseline" style="margin: 10px; float: right; border: 0px" width="200" height="143" /></a>I'm looking forward to meeting up with them. In 2003, I had a chance to share the stage with these great bluegrass players and the late <a href="http://www.vassarclements.com/">Vassar Clements</a> at the <a href="http://elkhenge.com/">Elkhenge Music Festival</a> in WV. If you are into authentic bluegrass, don't miss their show.</p>

<p>Support Texas Music this summer - Its going to be a good one!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[In search of a better photo gallery]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessecravens.com/blog/2006/03/31/in-search-of-a-better-photo-gallery/"/>
    <updated>2006-03-31T18:30:06-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessecravens.com/blog/2006/03/31/in-search-of-a-better-photo-gallery</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So digg and reddit have both posted on the work of Stu Nichols and his pure CSS photo gallery. Check it out: <a href="http://www.cssplay.co.uk/menu/lightbox.html#Trees">here</a>. I'm anxious to try it out. I'd like to find a way to blend this image gallery with a liquid three column layout, but the gallery is fixed - so it may have to be implemented on an internal page. Although, it would be interesting to have this image gallery present on a home page - since before the hover it only takes up the room of a horizontal menu. I'll be exploring this idea further - stay tuned.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[minishowcase: Ajax PhotoGallery]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessecravens.com/blog/2006/03/08/minishowcase-ajax-photogallery/"/>
    <updated>2006-03-08T06:35:19-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessecravens.com/blog/2006/03/08/minishowcase-ajax-photogallery</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Check out this ajax photogallery: <a href="http://minishowcase.backpackit.com/pub/367875">minishowcase</a>. It's lightweight, easy to customize, and a piece of cake to get up an running in no time. I removed the enormous Gallery2 from my server and replaced it with minishowcase. I lost the theming of Gallery 2, but minishowcase theming is on the way, and it wouldn't take much to create your own from scratch. Download also included easy to customize .css file.</p>

<p>For now it is fully functional in its own page <a href="http://jessecravens.com/gallery/">here</a>, but I will intgrate it as time permits.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gallery2 plug-in for Wordpress]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessecravens.com/blog/2006/01/31/gallery2-plug-in-for-wordpress/"/>
    <updated>2006-01-31T20:50:02-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessecravens.com/blog/2006/01/31/gallery2-plug-in-for-wordpress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://gallery.menalto.com/themes/gmc/logo.png" alt="Gallery2" /></p>

<p>I installed and configured the <a href="http://wpg2.ozgreg.com/index.php/Main_Page">gallery2 plug-in</a> today for Wordpress 2.0. I used the classic gallery 2 theme with the zen minimalist wordpress theme. There were a few tricks to get things working.</p>

<p>First of all, you need to have url paths turned off in order for gallery to show images inside the wordpress theme.
Also it may be necessary to set a minimum size for pictures to prevent a larger picture from breaking your page....obviously depending on the template that you use. Feel free to <a href="mailto:jesse.cravens@gmail.com">email me</a> for help.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
