<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: lyrics | Jesse Cravens]]></title>
  <link href="http://jessecravens.github.io/blog/categories/lyrics/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jessecravens.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-12-26T19:52:40-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://jessecravens.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jesse Cravens]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[jesse.cravens@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Goosebumps]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessecravens.github.io/blog/2006/04/22/goosebumps/"/>
    <updated>2006-04-22T20:10:52-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessecravens.github.io/blog/2006/04/22/goosebumps</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A whole lotta searchin' and a little bit of lookin'
In the barrooms, poolhalls, churches and schools,
Aint' never found no woman who could keep my attention,
That could make me crazy – make me act like a fool.
I’m in love with livin’,  and I aint’ afraid of nothing,
I keep on movin’ so life don’t get slow.
This game seems tricky and I might be a bit picky,
But when I finally meet her Ill sure as hell know.</p>

<p>And then you look down deep in my eyes,
and you smile at me that way.
All I can do is look back in your eyes,
Push your hair behind your ears,
You give me goosebumps when you smile.</p>

<p>Now I&rsquo;m reflecting, on that little bit of lookin',
But I don’t remember some of the places I&rsquo;ve been,
If I aint been learnin from all the decisions Ive been makin',
It&rsquo;s time I learned to live with who I am.
Now I’m relivin’ all those good times I was havin’,
And all the lessons I learned from the people on the road.
I might be crazy, a little bit lazy,
I&rsquo;m finally admittin’ to myself I’m sick of being alone.</p>

<p>Bridge:
I used to keep on running,
I’d run and run until I wore holes right through my shoes.
Yeah I used to keep on running,
Until I met you, that was all I knew.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hitchin' A Ride to Texas]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessecravens.github.io/blog/2006/04/22/hitchin-a-ride-to-texas/"/>
    <updated>2006-04-22T20:01:26-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessecravens.github.io/blog/2006/04/22/hitchin-a-ride-to-texas</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m hitchin' a ride all the way to Texas,
Dusk turns to night, I&rsquo;m hopin' my thumb will stop a ride.
If this was the first time, I might be surprised,
Now I know the difference between yall&rsquo;s life and mine,
I keep telling myself this is the way its supposed to be,
The challenge of the new road is my destiny,
And the only thought that kills the pain and gets me through the night,
Is the thought of yall' keepin' those dreams insight.
With the foothills in the rearview, and Raton around the bend,
I cant help but to think this might be the end.
Trying to keep my weary mind off those high lonesome sounds,
Every mans soul is meant to shine, you&rsquo;ll never force it down,
The open roads a hollerin' my name in the still of the night,
There aint' nothing like that humm -it just sounds so right,
I&rsquo;m hitchin' a ride all the way back to Texas.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[the Manatee]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessecravens.github.io/blog/2006/04/22/the-manatee/"/>
    <updated>2006-04-22T19:56:37-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessecravens.github.io/blog/2006/04/22/the-manatee</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In a baby blue trailer in East Texas pines,
Can&rsquo;t remember the bad, can&rsquo;t forget the good times,
Aint' no hot water, aint' no TV,
Were lovin’ life in the Manatee.</p>

<p>Breakfast at noon and lunch at three,
And the cheapest damn beer we ever did drink,
Common folk they just can’t see,
How were lovin’ life in the Manatee.</p>

<p>And the more we sing, and the more we play,
The more we realize it aint' about the race,
One life to live in this here place,
We might as well have a smilin’ face.</p>

<p>A case of Lone Star and some rice and beans,
Bellys a bulgin’, we got enough eat.
Aint no hot water, aint no TV,
Were lovin’ life in the Manatee.</p>

<p>The chickens are smellin, and the neighbors are a yellin’,
Where the dogs are?  There aint no tellin’,
Common folk, they just can’t see
How were lovin’ life in the Manatee.</p>

<p>And the more we sing, and the more we play,
The more we realize it aint about the race.
One life to live in this here place,
We might as well have a smilin’ face.</p>

<p>Aint no hot water, aint no TV,
Were lovin’ life in the Manatee.</p>

<p>Common folk they just cant see,
How we’re lovin’ life in the Manatee.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Conquer]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessecravens.github.io/blog/2006/04/22/conquer/"/>
    <updated>2006-04-22T19:49:27-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessecravens.github.io/blog/2006/04/22/conquer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&hellip;lyrics were adapted from the poem When Wicked Winds Weather</p>

<p>When your mad about the system
Apathy is your biggest mistake
When your mad about the system
You can turn that rage into change</p>

<p>Its time that we all conquered our fears</p>

<p>When the political minds are erasing
The truth in front of all of our eyes
In years to come we will be facing
The harsh realities without the lies and disguise</p>

<p>Its time that we all conquered our fears</p>

<p>Fortress built around a persona,
Eroded Freedoms, Intuitions thought twice,
Hesitated streams of consciousness,
Interrupted to begin, again and again</p>

<p>Its time that we all conquered our fears</p>

<p>Is it not ironic that we‘ve squandered
Any notions of a matriarchy
When our Mother’s milks are running low
Yes,  our Mother’s milks are running low</p>

<p>Were making mincemeat of evil
Spoon-feeding the ice cream through glowing TV’s
A feasible feast when a Giant
Amongst a miniscule Pharisee.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
