<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Books | Jesse Cravens]]></title>
  <link href="http://jessecravens.com/blog/categories/books/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jessecravens.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-26T11:43:18-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://jessecravens.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jesse Cravens]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[jesse.cravens@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Just moved HTML5 Hacks into Copy/Edit]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessecravens.com/blog/2012/09/24/just-moved-html5-hacks-into-copy-slash-edit/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-24T21:57:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessecravens.com/blog/2012/09/24/just-moved-html5-hacks-into-copy-slash-edit</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After a marathon of hackery starting in April, <a href="http://www.oreillynet.com/pub/au/5370">Jeff Burtoft</a> and I pushed out 90 hacks and 435 pages of <a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920026273.do">HTML5 Hacks</a> this week. We also had a few guest hackers that created some really great content as well.</p>

<ul>
<li>Raymond Camden of Adobe</li>
<li>Phil Legetter of Pusher.com</li>
<li>Alexander Schulze of jWebsocket</li>
<li><a href="http://j.hn/">John Dyer</a> of Dallas Theological Seminary</li>
<li>Alex Sirota of FoxyTunes</li>
</ul>


<p>Overall, it was a great experience. What I enjoyed the most was getting into a workflow groove, much like when you are building an API or contributing to a project. With each hack, it was necessary to ideate, plan, create the code, test it, and then put it into a understandable format. By the end, I was feeling pretty efficient at kicking out interesting hacks pretty quickly.</p>

<p>I felt as though I improved over time, looking back is always interesting. I like to keep fine tuning and revising, but at some point you have to ship the product. I'm really proud of the work, it has been hard, but I learned a ton in the process.</p>

<p>Most of my hacks I tried to make relevant to real world software development challenges, and mix in a number of HTML5 specifications. Hopefully, that turns out to benefit the reader ... I'm all ears on the feedback. So don't hesitate to drop us a line.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
