<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Boerne | Jesse Cravens]]></title>
  <link href="http://jessecravens.com/blog/categories/boerne/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jessecravens.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-02-03T23:36:26-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://jessecravens.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jesse Cravens]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[jesse.cravens@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[In Search of A Balance: Integrating the Sudbury and other democratic models with Moodle]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessecravens.com/blog/2006/11/17/in-search-of-a-balance-integrating-the-sudbury-and-other-democratic-models-with-moodle/"/>
    <updated>2006-11-17T06:57:33-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessecravens.com/blog/2006/11/17/in-search-of-a-balance-integrating-the-sudbury-and-other-democratic-models-with-moodle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm definitely into the hybrid thing lately. Hybrid instruction not only in the sense of implementation: online and face to face learning through moodle (http://moodle.org) and short class lectures/discussions, but also philosophically in a sense of allowing students to have some type of control over the curriculum, and direction of their own study. Every moodle assignment I offer, is open to interpretation and creativity. This is why I believe that rubrics can potentially take the fun out of learning. They limit learners to the parameters made by the teacher. Especially when we are teaching technoloies that are more native to the learner than the educator. <br /><br />This article takes a neutral approach to - what I will call the Sudbury model, but really applies to many other free, democratic school models. I agree with both sides of the argument, and I have settled on balance and moderation of both freedom and standardization. This combined with a balance between face to face and elearning and I think we might make some real progress in my classroom. <br /><a href="http://www.edutopia.org/magazine/ed1article.php?id=Art_1615&amp;issue=oct_06">Free Radicals</a> <br /> <blockquote>In the country's most alternative classrooms, there's no such thing as a report card.</p>

<br /><br />Sudbury schools are only one variety of so-called free, or democratic, schools, which eschew most conventions of traditional education in favor of a much more radical program. At most free schools, literally every decision, from those about staff hiring and firing to determinations concerning rules, facilities, and budget issues, is made by the entire school community in a one-person, one-vote process. There are no tests, no report cards, no requirements, and no classes -- and no curriculum, other than what students set for themselves.




<br /><br />It is a philosophy that may strike the uninitiated as far-fetched, if not irresponsible, but it seems to be working.......

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[iBoerne.com selected for 2007 TCEA Convention student showcase]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessecravens.com/blog/2006/11/15/iboerne-com-selected-for-2007-tcea-convention-student-showcase/"/>
    <updated>2006-11-15T07:36:10-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessecravens.com/blog/2006/11/15/iboerne-com-selected-for-2007-tcea-convention-student-showcase</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Congratulations to my students for their great work on iBoerne.com. Our submission for Student Showcase
has been accepted for the 2007 TCEA Convention !<br /><br /><a href="http://jessecravens.com/node/79">iBoerne.com: an Interactive Online Game for Programming Students | jessecravens.com</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digett pays my BCP class a visit]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessecravens.com/blog/2006/11/09/digett-pays-my-bcp-class-a-visit/"/>
    <updated>2006-11-09T11:20:26-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessecravens.com/blog/2006/11/09/digett-pays-my-bcp-class-a-visit</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://digett.com/news/boerne-schools-test-the-waters-with-new-web-based-learning-environment">Boerne Schools Test the Waters with New Web-based Learning Environment | Digett</a><br /><br />My business computer programming class was fortunate to have Mark Figart of Digett as a guest speaker, yesterday. The students are preparing a podcast from the audio recording of the question and answer sessions. The students asked great questions and documented their responses as assignement entries in our <a href="http://boernevirtualschool.com">Boerne Virtual School</a> Moodle course. We are looking forward to having other speakers from the local Boerne business community. <br /><br /><br /><p class="poweredbyperformancing">powered by <a href="http://performancing.com/firefox">performancing firefox</a></p></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[iBoerne.com: an Interactive Online Game for Programming Students]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessecravens.com/blog/2006/10/10/iboerne-com-an-interactive-online-game-for-programming-students/"/>
    <updated>2006-10-10T07:13:22-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessecravens.com/blog/2006/10/10/iboerne-com-an-interactive-online-game-for-programming-students</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://iboerne.com"><img style="float:left; margin: 10px" src="http://jessecravens.com/images/jessecravens/iboerne_150.jpg"></a><a href="http://iboerne.com">iBoerne.com</a> is a mashup of Google maps and Drupal using the drupal gmap module to create virtual competition between teams of students. The teams are: Yellow, Red, Green, Blue. The rules of the game were created to encourage the six member teams to discuss concepts such as project management, virtual teams, workflow, efficiency, and collaboration tools.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Texas Hill Country Music as of Lately]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessecravens.com/blog/2006/05/24/texas-hill-country-music-as-of-lately/"/>
    <updated>2006-05-24T17:37:20-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessecravens.com/blog/2006/05/24/texas-hill-country-music-as-of-lately</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.mytexasmusic.com/rodneyjoesmith/"><img src="http://jessecravens.com/images/2006/02/rodneypic250.jpg" style="margin: 10px; float: right; border: 0px" alt="rodneypic250.jpg" align="baseline" width="200" height="247" /></a>This morning I ate breakfast listening to Rodney Joe Smith at our Digett sponsored Boerne Chamber of Commerce Networking Breakfast at <a href="http://enchantedspringsranch.com">Enchanted Springs Ranch</a>.  Boy, Rodney can sing and play. It was a real pleasure.</p>

<p>I also had a pleasure to meet Lynn Myers: Guitar, Fiddle, Vocalist &amp; Band Director of the <a href="http://www.1000hillscc.com/band.html">Thousand Hills Cowboy Church Band</a>.
I love that ol' Country Gospel music and I am looking forward to checking him and the band out soon.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.1000hillscc.com/band.html"><img src="http://jessecravens.com/images/2006/02/2_bandb.jpg" alt="2_bandb.jpg" align="baseline" width="200" height="298" style="margin: 10px; float: left; border: 0px"/></a>This evening, I had a chance to sit down with <a href="http://harleydean.com/index.php">Harley Dean</a> and play some country bass lines from his album, There and Back Again. I like Harley's songwriting and he has a great singing voice.<a href="http://harleydean.com"><img src="http://jessecravens.com/images/2006/02/home_image.jpg" alt="home_image.jpg" style="margin: 10px; float: right; border: 0px" align="baseline" width="220" height="120" /></a></p>

<p>In the meantime, the Digett team will be enjoying the tunes of client, Joel Rafeal (<a href="http://www.joelrafael.com/">http://www.joelrafael.com/</a>) this Friday at the <a href="http://www.kerrvillefolkfestival.com/">Kerrville Folk Festival</a>.</p>

<p>Next week, I'll be at the <a href="http://www.kerrville-music.com/rootsbluesclinic.htm">Roots/Blues Workshop</a> in Kerrville Tues - Thur. I'm looking forward to meeting <a href="http://www.suefoley.com/">Sue Foley,</a> <a href="http://www.thadbeckman.com/">Thad Beckman</a>, <a href="http://www.stevejames.com/">Steve James</a> and the other instructors, and learning some new licks and techniques.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.northernlightsband.com/">The Northern Lights</a> will also be down from New England for the festival. <a href="http://www.northernlightsband.com/"><img src="http://jessecravens.com/images/2006/02/NLband.jpg" alt="NLband.jpg" align="baseline" style="margin: 10px; float: right; border: 0px" width="200" height="143" /></a>I'm looking forward to meeting up with them. In 2003, I had a chance to share the stage with these great bluegrass players and the late <a href="http://www.vassarclements.com/">Vassar Clements</a> at the <a href="http://elkhenge.com/">Elkhenge Music Festival</a> in WV. If you are into authentic bluegrass, don't miss their show.</p>

<p>Support Texas Music this summer - Its going to be a good one!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
