<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: curriculum | Jesse Cravens]]></title>
  <link href="http://jessecravens.com/blog/categories/curriculum/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jessecravens.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-21T18:56:56-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://jessecravens.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jesse Cravens]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[jesse.cravens@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[EduPunk]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessecravens.com/blog/2009/03/15/edupunk/"/>
    <updated>2009-03-15T12:22:26-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessecravens.com/blog/2009/03/15/edupunk</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<object width="445" height="364"><param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/f7MxVqe_uRI&hl=en&fs=1&border=1"></param><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"></param><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"></param><embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/f7MxVqe_uRI&hl=en&fs=1&border=1" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" width="445" height="364"></embed></object>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Top 5 Free Computer and Technology Books Lists for High School and College Computer Classes]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessecravens.com/blog/2007/06/15/top-5-free-computer-and-technology-books-lists-for-high-school-and-college-computer-classes/"/>
    <updated>2007-06-15T13:49:14-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessecravens.com/blog/2007/06/15/top-5-free-computer-and-technology-books-lists-for-high-school-and-college-computer-classes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Is it really necessary to purchase text books for those computer classes anymore? Take a look at your content area on each of these sites. You be the judge. </p>


<p></p>

<ul>
<li>1. <a href="http://freecomputerbooks.com/">freecomputerbooks.com</a></li>  

<li>2. <a href="http://www.freetechbooks.com/">freetechbooks.com</a> </li>  

<li>3. <a href="http://www.techtoolblog.com/archives/195-free-online-programming-books">techtoolblog.com</a></li>  

<li>4. <a href="http://www.computer-books.us/">computer-books.us</a> </li>  

<li>5. <a href="http://www.onlinecomputerbooks.com/">onlinecomputerbooks.com</a> </li>
<ul>  

<p>...as this list expands keep track here: <a href="http://del.icio.us/cravens/freebook">del.icio.us/cravens/freebook</a>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is College Worth It?]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessecravens.com/blog/2006/12/07/is-college-worth-it/"/>
    <updated>2006-12-07T16:01:17-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessecravens.com/blog/2006/12/07/is-college-worth-it</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.aboutreef.org/is-college-worth-it.html">Is College Worth It?</a><br /><br />This article takes a look at the decision of investing in an education. It doesn't consider the social aspect of the college experience, but simply the return on the investment.<br /><br /></p>

<pre><code>                              The analysis begins by assessing a college education purely as a
                              monetary investment. Undoubtedly, there are other benefits beyond money
                              to attend college, but it's such an enormous economic decision that it
                              seems foolish to not fully understand the financial ramifications and
                              use that as a primary factor in the decision process.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p class="poweredbyperformancing"&gt;powered by &lt;a href="http://performancing.com/firefox"&gt;performancing firefox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[In Search of A Balance: Integrating the Sudbury and other democratic models with Moodle]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessecravens.com/blog/2006/11/17/in-search-of-a-balance-integrating-the-sudbury-and-other-democratic-models-with-moodle/"/>
    <updated>2006-11-17T06:57:33-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessecravens.com/blog/2006/11/17/in-search-of-a-balance-integrating-the-sudbury-and-other-democratic-models-with-moodle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm definitely into the hybrid thing lately. Hybrid instruction not only in the sense of implementation: online and face to face learning through moodle (http://moodle.org) and short class lectures/discussions, but also philosophically in a sense of allowing students to have some type of control over the curriculum, and direction of their own study. Every moodle assignment I offer, is open to interpretation and creativity. This is why I believe that rubrics can potentially take the fun out of learning. They limit learners to the parameters made by the teacher. Especially when we are teaching technoloies that are more native to the learner than the educator. <br /><br />This article takes a neutral approach to - what I will call the Sudbury model, but really applies to many other free, democratic school models. I agree with both sides of the argument, and I have settled on balance and moderation of both freedom and standardization. This combined with a balance between face to face and elearning and I think we might make some real progress in my classroom. <br /><a href="http://www.edutopia.org/magazine/ed1article.php?id=Art_1615&amp;issue=oct_06">Free Radicals</a> <br /> <blockquote>In the country's most alternative classrooms, there's no such thing as a report card.</p>

<br /><br />Sudbury schools are only one variety of so-called free, or democratic, schools, which eschew most conventions of traditional education in favor of a much more radical program. At most free schools, literally every decision, from those about staff hiring and firing to determinations concerning rules, facilities, and budget issues, is made by the entire school community in a one-person, one-vote process. There are no tests, no report cards, no requirements, and no classes -- and no curriculum, other than what students set for themselves.




<br /><br />It is a philosophy that may strike the uninitiated as far-fetched, if not irresponsible, but it seems to be working.......

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Teaching and Learning TechForum: Austin, Tx - October 27th, 2006]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessecravens.com/blog/2006/11/09/teaching-and-learning-techforum-austin-tx-october-27th-2006/"/>
    <updated>2006-11-09T12:56:58-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessecravens.com/blog/2006/11/09/teaching-and-learning-techforum-austin-tx-october-27th-2006</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some of the highlights from my recent visit with educators at the Texas Tech Forum included:<br /><br /><a href="http://davidwarlick.com/wordpress/?page_id=2">David Warlick</a>:&nbsp; An Educator's Guide to Web 2.0<br /><br /><a href="http://www.paxwarrior.com/home/index.php">:: Pax home page :: || :: Pax Warrior ::</a> <br /><br />Pax Warrior is a Hybrid New Media product for the educational and training markets that extends the nascent "Interactive Documentary" form to incorporate decision based simulation and collaborative learning tools. It is at the lead of the new genre of "Serious Games".<br /><br />There was also quite a bit of a buzz over Linux, primariliy <a href="http://www.edubuntu.org/">edubuntu</a>. I recently installed edubuntu in my classroom and used it to begin a lesson on operating systems. I would be very excited about an opportunity to use older pcs to build a linux learning lab.<br /><br />I'm using moodle to manage the <a href="http://boernevirtualschool.com">Boerne Virtual School</a>, so I took a little time to share my experience with other educators and to invite progrmaming teachers to join our class online.&nbsp; &nbsp;  <br /><br /><br /><p class="poweredbyperformancing">powered by <a href="http://performancing.com/firefox">performancing firefox</a></p></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
